Hettger, Henry T.; Papers mss150
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Henry T. Hettger Papers
1976-2016
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
mss150
.8 cubic ft.
The Henry T. Hettger Papers document Hettger's published and unpublished contributions to various numismatic publications, his coin purchases, and various correspondence.
Content Description
This collection contains published and unpublished manuscripts written by Henry T. Hettinger, periodical clippings, related correspondence, and research materials
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Henry T. Hettger donated all materials in this collection in March 2023.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is largely organized chronologically and separated based on publication status. Most articles were stapled together with related materials (research materials, original manuscripts, relevant correspondence, published clippings…). The donor/creator made notes about article status, but could not always recall if an article had been published. If an article was more likely to be unpublished, it was placed in an 'unpublished' folder. If an article was more likely to be published, it was placed in a 'published' folder. Larger research projects were placed in their own folders and labeled by title. Correspondence not related to article creation was placed in a separate folder.
Biographical Note
Henry T. Hettger received an MPA from the University at Albany in 1968. After graduating, he worked extensively in the field of government and private sectors, including a brief assignment with the Office of Presidential Personnel and President Jimmy Carter's Affirmative Action Project in 1977 before becoming a researcher for the National Archives and Records Administration. At the age of 12, Hettger inherited his grandfather's coin collection. This sparked a lifelong love of numismatics. Alongside avid coin collecting, he has authored over 100 articles for Numismatic News, collector newsletters, and Open Archeology, a peer-reviewed journal. He is also a member of the Early American Coppers club and particularly interested in large cents.
Hettger, Henry T.; Coins--Collectors and collecting; UAlbany Faculty & Alumni Papers; Correspondence; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Manuscripts
- Published Publications, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Published Publications, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Unpublished Materials, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Published Publications, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Unpublished Materials, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1991-2016; Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Published Publications, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Unpublished Materials, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Published Publications, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Unpublished Materials, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- "Money Talks" (Radio Program), 1993-1994; 1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Published Publications, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Unpublished Materials, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- "The Challenge of Numismatic Diversity found in the Comoro Islands" (Unpublished), 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Published Publications, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Unpublished Materials, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Published Publications, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Unpublished Materials, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Published Publications, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Unpublished Materials, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Published Publications, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Unpublished Materials, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Notes and Research, 1998; Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Published Publications, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Unpublished Materials, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Published Publications, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Unpublished Materials, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Published Publications, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Published Publications, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Unpublished Materials, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Published Publications, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Published Publications, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Unpublished Materials, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Published Publications, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Unpublished Materials, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Published Publications, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Published Publications, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Published Publications, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Unpublished Materials, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Unpublished Materials, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- "Complete List of Known Lettered Edge Errors/Blunders on Early Large Cents", Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Sold or Published Articles, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)